<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: jekyll | ROCKAGEN]]></title>
  <link href="http://rockagen.github.com/blog/categories/jekyll/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rockagen.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-05T10:39:52+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://rockagen.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[ra]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bloging like a Hacker]]></title>
    <link href="http://rockagen.github.com/blog/2012/06/27/bloging-like-a-hacker/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-27T03:48:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://rockagen.github.com/blog/2012/06/27/bloging-like-a-hacker</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back in 2000,  when I thought I was going to be a professional writer,  I spent hours a day on LiveJournal doing writing practice with other aspiring poets and authors. Since then I've blogged at three different domains about web standards,  print design,  photography,  Flash,  illustration,  information architecture,  ColdFusion,  package management,  PHP,  CSS,  advertising,  Ruby,  Rails,  and Erlang.</p>

<p>I love writing. I get a kick out of sharing my thoughts with others. The act of transforming ideas into words is an amazingly efficient way to solidify and refine your thoughts about a given topic. But as much as I enjoy blogging,  I seem to be stuck in a cycle of quitting and starting over. Before starting the current iteration,  I resolved to do some introspection to determine the factors that were leading to this destructive pattern.</p>

<p>I already knew a lot about what I <em>didn't</em> want. I was tired of complicated blogging engines like WordPress and Mephisto. I wanted to write great posts,  not style a zillion template pages,  moderate comments all day long,  and constantly lag behind the latest software release. Something like Posterous looked attractive,  but I wanted to style my blog,  and it needed to be hosted at the domain of my choosing. For the same reason,  other hosted sites (wordpress.com,  blogger.com) were disqualified. There are a few people directly using GitHub as a blog (which is very cool),  but that's a bit too much of an impedance mismatch for my tastes.</p>

<p>On Sunday,  October 19th,  I sat down in my San Francisco apartment with a glass of apple cider and a clear mind. After a period of reflection,  I had an idea. While I'm not specifically trained as an author of prose,  I <em>am</em> trained as an author of code. What would happen if I approached blogging from a software development perspective? What would that look like?</p>

<p>..</p>

<p><a href="http://tom.preston-werner.com/2008/11/17/blogging-like-a-hacker.html" title="blogin like a hacker">source</a></p>

<hr />

<p>fork <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">
<img src="https://github.com/favicon.ico" alt="" />
</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
